嘘
次回予告
Geez...
まったく　何でいまさら志願生と一緒になって訓練だなんて
Why do I have to train alongside the recruits and volunteers?
I didn't join Judgement for this crap...
<Judgement>
こんなことのためにジャッジメントになったわけではありませんのに
Hey, Uiharu.
ほら　初春　一回もできんのか
Come on, can't you do at least one push-up?
Take some if you want.
宜しければ どうぞ
So you've already been a member of Judgement for a year, Shirai-san?
<Judgement>
へぇ～　白井さんはジャッジメントになって　もう一年なんですか
You've already been out in the field and produced results, then.
じゃあ　もう現場に出て活躍されてるんですね
O-Oh, of course.
もちろんですの
I'm not going to make the cut, am I?
やっぱり　私みたいのじゃ無理なんですかね
I'm clumsy.
私トロくって
I signed up thinking that I might be able to change if I joined Judgement.
<Judgement>
でもジャッジメントになれば
そんな私でも変われるんじゃないかって志願したんですけど
But I can't even keep up with the training.
訓練に全然着いていけなくて
Just do what you believe is right.
己の信念に従い　正しいと感じた行動を取るべし
<Judgement>
ジャッジメントの心得の一つですの
That's one of the principles of Judgement.
思いを貫き通す意志があるなら　結果は後からついてきますわ
If you're strong enough to follow what you believe,
then results will come naturally.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
Special Notice: Beware of car break-ins
Recently, there have been many break-ins into parked cars. Always keep valuables with you when leaving your car.
えーと　ほかに設置が必要な場所は
Umm...
It needs to be installed where, again?
あそことあそこですね
There and there.
まったく　今の今まで監視カメラの増設を放置していただなんて
Geez.
I can't believe they've neglected installing additional security cameras for this long.
この学校のジャッジメントはずいぶんのんびり屋さんですの
The Judgement members at this school must be really lax.
でも　被害が出る前でよかったですよ
Well, I guess it's good that nothing's happened yet.
そういう問題ではありません
That's not the issue.
行きますわよ
Let's go!
はい
Right!
Geez...
<Judgement>
まったく　白昼堂堂と 学内　あまつさえジャッジメントの前で
In broad daylight? At school? Right in front of Judgement members?
白井さん駄目です
Shirai-san, you mustn't!
応援が来るまで待ってください
Please wait until reinforcements arrive.
問題ありませんの　初春はここで待機を
It'll be fine.
Wait here, Uiharu.
はい　そこまでですわ
Okay, that's it.
Huh?
<Judgement>
ジャッジメントですの
This is Judgement.
器物損害および窃盗の現行犯で拘束します
You are under arrest for destruction of property and theft.
Please be careful.
気をつけてください　相手は一人とは
We don't know if he has accomplices or not.
It doesn't really matter how many of them there are.
相手が何人だろうと　車上荒らしごとき　ちょちょいのちょいですわ
They're just some petty thieves. Nothing too difficult.
さぁ～　大人しくしてくださいな　悪いようにはしま
All right, please cooperate.
I'll make sure you're treated-
白井さん
Shirai-san!
Hey! We're getting out of here!
おい～　連れてるぞ
Yeah!
P-Please stop!
と　停まってください
どけ
Out of my way!
初春?
Uiharu?
初春　初春　しっかりしますの
Uiharu!
Pull yourself together!
初春
Uiharu?
I-I'm fine...
だい　大丈夫です
まったく　寿命が少し縮みましたわよ
Geez...
You scared the hell out of me.
車上荒らしは
Where'd the thieves go?
もう逃げましたわ
They already escaped.
まったく
Geez.
やはり　初春はまだまだ半人前ですの
Looks like you're still not capable of flying solo.
今まで通り　支部で私のバックアップをしてればいいのですわ
It's back to being backup in the branch office for you.
私　私だって　私だって
I-I told you...
I-I told you that they might not be alone.
相手が一人とは限らないって言いました
それを無視したのは　白井さんじゃないですか
You're the one who ignored my advice!
それは
Well...
You're always like this!
大体白井さんはいつもそうです
無茶して独断専行ばっかり　だから始末書の数が減らないんですよ
You're reckless! You just rush into things on your own!
That's why we have to write so many apology letters...
Hey, I take offense at that.
き　聞き捨てなりませんわね
私がいつ独断専行しだと
Do you have an example of me "rushing into things?"
Well?
いつって　いつもじゃないですか
Always!
今回だって応援が来るまで待ってもよかったのに
For example, you could have waited for reinforcements to arrive earlier!
That'd take too long!
そんな悠長なこと犯人に逃げられてしまいますの
They'll escape!
少しは反省してください
Can you please think about what you've done?
このままじゃ私たちの約束はどうなるんですか
How are we supposed to fulfill our promise like this?
約束
Promise...?
覚えてないんですか
You don't remember?
はって
Hmm...
分かりました　白井さんがそういう考えならもう知りません
Fine then!
If you're going to be like that, then I'm washing my hands of this entire affair!
へぇ
Do whatever you want!
勝ってにしてください
Mmm?
こんにちは 初春 来てますか
Hello!
Is Uiharu here?
またあなた　まったく　ここは溜まり場じゃないのよ
Oh, it's you again.
This isn't exactly a place to be hanging out, I hope you realize.
はいはい　分かってます
Yes, I understand.
でも　今日はちゃんと理由が
I have a valid reason today, though.
ジャン　あたしの補修プリント
Look!
This is the additional homework I was assigned!
初春に手伝ってもらおうと思って
I wanted her to help me out.
たっく
Geez.
初春さんなら　ほら
She's over there.
でも今は止めといたほうがいいかも
It might not be a good idea to ask her about it right now, though...
初春さんちょっと機嫌が
She's a bit upset...
う　い　は　る
Uiharu~n!
お　今日はクローバー
Oh, you're wearing clovers today?
よし　幸せの四葉のクローバーはどこかな
Lemme find the lucky four leaf clover!
って　ほれほれ　めくってるよ　絶景だよ
Uh... earth to Uiharu. Look, I'm pulling your skirt up.
The view from here is great.
What's gotten into her?
初春はどうしちゃったんですか
白井さんといろいろあって
Something happened between her and Shirai-san...
ちょっとね
She's a bit...
そんなことがあったんですか
Oh, I hadn't heard.
そういうこと
Yeah.
だから少しそっとしといて上げて
So, can you let her be alone for a while?
<Judgement>
だったらもいっそのこと　ジャッジメントやめちゃえばいいのに
She should just quit Judgement!
ちょっと　ちょっと　無責任なこと言わないで
Hey, wait!
Don't go putting weird ideas into her head!
<Judgement>　　　　　<antiskill>
ジャッジメントは　アンチスキルと並ぶ 学院都市の治安維持機関なのよ
The members of Judgement and the Anti-skills are tasked with protecting the Academy City.
かってに放り出したり出来る仕事じゃないわ
They can't just go quitting their jobs all willy-nilly.
じゃ　このままほっとくしかないですか
Then what are we supposed to do, just leave her like this?
そういうわけには行かないけど
Well, no, but...
まあ　大丈夫だと思うわよ
...Honestly, I think it'll all work out in the end.
え？　あの二人なんかあるんですか
Oh? Is there some secret between them?
聞きたい
Do you want to hear about it?
あ～～もう うっとうしい
Argh! So annoying!
あんたね　そんなに気になるなら とっとと仲直りしてくればいいじゃない
Hey, if it pisses you off this much, why don't you just go make up with her?
Well...
それは
このままだと　初春さん　あんたに愛想尽かして
If you just leave it like this, Uiharu-san might really give up on you.
本当にコンビ解消しちゃうかもよ
You know, break up the partnership.
これぐらいで終るんなら
If our partnership can be broken off so easily,
所詮その程度の関係だったということですわ
then I guess it wasn't very strong to begin with.
またそんな強がりを
Stop trying to show off.
I'm not!
強がってませんの
Actually, just why are you two partners?
あんたと初春さんって　そこまで性格違うのに
何でコンビなんか組んでるのよ
You're both really different.
I-I never...
私だって
最初はそんなつもりありませんでしたの
...intended to become partners with her.
あんなにとろくて　何も出来ない子
She's such a clumsy and useless girl.
ですけれど
However...
7th Academy District
3rd Branch office
はい　今日の巡回はこれでお仕舞い
Okay, this concludes today's patrol.
なにかきになったことや質問とかある
Do you have any questions or concerns?
では　少しお聞きしたいのですが
I'd like to ask you something.
なに？
What is it?
It's been over a year since I joined Judgement.
<Judgement>
ジャッジメントになって一年にもなりますのに
なんで私に任されるのは 裏方や雑用、先輩同伴のパトロールばかりですの
Why do you only let me work behind the scenes? I want to do more than just simple errands and patrols.
成績優秀な自分が半人前扱いされるのが不満
In other words, you're frustrated that you're not being given jobs that let your full potential shine?
W-well, not exactly, but...
そういうわけではありませんが
...I thought it might be just because I'm still in elementary school.
やはり私がまだ小学生だからかと
年齢だけが問題じゃないわ
It's not just a matter of age.
あなたの場合　なまじポテンシャルが高い分
In your case... well, you have a lot of potential, so you try to solve everything by yourself.
すべてを一人で解決しようとする嫌いがあるからね
もう少し周りの人間を頼りようにならないと危なっかしいのよ
We feel that you're at risk until you learn to trust others to help you out.
ほら　そんな顔しないの
Hey, stop looking like that.
たくさん頑張ったご褒美に　なんかあまい物奢ってあげる
You did a good job today, so I'll treat you to something sweet.
お金おろしてくるから　ちょっと待ってて
I'll go withdraw some money. Wait here for me.
やっぱり子供扱いされてますの
She really does treat me like a kid.
7th Academic District
3rd branch office
ATM
は　白井さん　偶然ですね
Oh, Shirai-san!
What a coincidence!
初春　何であなたが第七学区に
Uiharu?
Why are you in the 7th Academic District?
もうすぐ中学生だし　学校や寮の下見に来たんです
I'm going to be a middle school student soon.
I came to scope out my future school and dormitory.
中学生　どなたがですの
Middle school student? Who is?
Me, of course!
私に決まってるじゃないですか　いやだな　もう
Come on.
Really...
へぇ～同い年でしたの
We're the same age?
二つ三つ年下だとばかり
I thought that you were a few years younger than me.
Shirai-san, do you know which middle school you'll be attending?
白井さんはもうどの中学に行くか決まったんか
え　常盤台中学と言う所に
Y-Yes.
A place called Tokiwadai Junior High School.
へ～～常盤台中学と言えば　学園都市でも五本の指に入れる名門校ですよ
Really?
Tokiwadai Junior High is one of the five most prestigious schools in the Academy City!
学院生活もきっと優雅なんでしょうね
I bet it's like, totally elegant!
I hear the reality isn't quite that wonderful.
実際はそんなきれいごとばかりではないようですわよ
Huh?
It's just a bunch of rich girls who know nothing about how the world works.
世間知らずの金持ちに 在校生全員がレベル3以上の能力者
Oh, and they're all over Level 3.
自分のことを特別な人間だと思っているの方たちが多く集まってるとか
I hear that everyone there thinks they're sooo special.
Really?
There's also some Level 5 called Railgun there.
<Railgun>　　　　　　　　<level 5>
中でもレールガンなどと呼ばれる超能力者がいるらしいのですが
She must be some arrogant, annoying bitch.
きっと高慢ちきで　いけ好かない性悪女に決まってますわ
知らない人のこと　よくそこまで言えますね
You're pretty harsh, badmouthing someone you don't even know...
そういえば　あなた　郵便局になに…
Come to think of it, what did you come to the post office-
どうしました
What's the matter?
ちょっと失礼
Excuse me for a second.
どうなさいました
What's the matter?
あの男
That man.
局員の場所や視線ばかり気にしてる
He seems to be only concerned about what the staff are up to and where they're positioned.
Huh?
人の所有物を無断で透視するのは気が引けるけど
I don't really like looking through people's possessions without their permission, but...
妙なものは持ってないようね
It looks like he doesn't have anything suspicious.
右ポケットに拳銃
He has a gun in his right pocket.
強盗ですの
Is he a robber?
局員に伝えて来るわ
I'll go tell the staff.
あなたが万が一に備えて　利用客の誘導準備を
You get ready to lead the customers to escape. Just in case.
逮捕しませんの
You aren't arresting him?
馬鹿なこと考えちゃだめよ
Don't get any funny ideas.
<antiskill>
犯人確保はアンチスキルに任せなさい
Leave the arrests to the Anti-skills.
そんな消極的な
We can't be so passive!
That's right.
<antiskill>
そうです　大至急アンチスキルれん……
Please call in the Anti-skills immediately.
可笑しな真似すんなよ　お客もあまり騒がないでくれよな
Don't make any sudden movements.
Y-you guys, too. Don't get too excited!
Damn it.
くそ　先に動かれた
He made his move.
訓練通りやれば
If I just do as I've been trained...
なんだ　テメェ
What the fuck are you-
何だ　簡単ではありませんの
That was pretty easy.
たっく　阿呆か
You're such an idiot!
何ガキに伸されてんだよ　使えねえ
Why are you letting some damn kid beat you up!?
So useless.
Uiharu!
初春
あら　お前の知り合いだったのか
Oh, is she an acquaintance of yours?
某
二
人
的
新
人
研
修
A Certain Scientific Railgun
#5
A certain pair's
newbie training
That's convenient.
こりゃ好都合
<Judgement>
ほっと　動くなよ　お前ジャッジメントか
Hey! Don't move!
Are you with Judgement?
<Judgement>
ジャッジメントが人質見捨てわけねえよな
Members of Judgement won't abandon hostages, of course.
ましてや　自分の知り合いを
Especially not if you know them personally.
最悪
他にも仲間がいるんじゃねえのか
Is there anyone else with you?
This is not good...
出てくるなら今のうちだぞ
Time to come out and play.
What?
Why are the shutters coming down?
何でしょうか
何のつもり　こんな状況で警報なんて
What are they planning?
They're sounding the alarm...
客の命よりお金のほうが大事だってんの
Do they care more about the money than the lives of the customers?
セキュリティ信号を受信しました
Security signal detected.
侵入者を排除します
Removing intruder.
武器を捨てて　床に伏せてください
Discard your weapon and lie on the ground.
って　面倒臭い
How troublesome...
右ポケットになにか
He has something in his right pocket.
警告完了　実行します
Warning complete.
Executing.
おっと
Oops.
なにが
What just happened...?
先輩
Senpai.
手の内が分からない間は　突入しない
You can't rush in...
...until you know what your opponent is capable of.
覚えときなさい
Remember that.
Wh-Why?
どうして
おい　やっぱ仲間がいったか
Hey.
So you did have backup!
白井さん
Shirai-san?
あの馬鹿みたいに　俺もやれると思ったのかよ
You thought it would be that easy? Are you an idiot?
白井さん
Shirai-san! No!
なめやがて
Damn you... Making a fool out of me like this...
白井さん　白井さん
Shirai-san!
もう止めてください
Please stop it!
Shirai-san!
私のせいですの
It's all my fault.
私の軽率な判断のせいで
Because I was thoughtless...
初春も　固法先輩も
Uiharu and Konori-senpai are going to...
やめて　止めてください　お願いします
Please stop! Please!
何で様ですの　半人前以下ではありませんか
How terrible.
Please!
I'm not even halfway capable...
たっく　余計な手間を
God. It's just one thing after another with you guys.
Shirai-san!
でも
But...
しつっけいな
Give it up, man.
もう　やめてください　もう
Please stop!
Now...
必ず　助けて見せますの
I'm gonna save you, no matter what.
は　何のつもりだ
What are you trying to-
What?
外
I'm outside?
<teleport>
テレポートだ
Teleporting?
白井さん　中にいるんですか
Shirai-san?
Are you still inside?
どうして私だけ
Why did you only let me escape?
Making such a fool out of me...
ふざけやがって
白井さんも早く外へ
Shirai-san, please teleport outside now!
I'd love to do so, but...
そうしたいのですけど　私まだ自分を飛ばせませんの
Unfortunately, I can't transport myself yet.
それに　事件をまだ解決してませんから
And, moreover... I haven't finished wrapping things up yet.
白井さん
Shirai-san!
誰か　お願いします
Someone, I beg you! Please help me!
助けてください
中に強盗が
There are robbers inside! The robbers are attacking members of Judgement!
ジャッジメントが強盗に襲われてて　助けてください
Please save them! I beg you!
お願いします
お前が何考えてるか当ててやろうか
Let me read your mind.
Huh?
<antiskill>
警報が鳴って大分経つ　そろそろアンチスキルも来る
The alarm got switched on quite a while ago.
The Anti-skills should be arriving soon.
人質を取られないよう　こいつを足止めできれば　こちらの勝ち
As long as I can make sure you can't take any hostages, it's our win.
図星だろう
I got it right, eh?
だがな　ここからでれないと決まったわけじゃなえだぜ
Wait just a second...
Who said that I couldn't leave?
What!?
<Equal Speed>
イコールスピード
Equal Speed.
俺が投げたものは それが壊れるか能力を解除するまで
Anything I throw will continue to travel, regardless of what's in its path, until the object is either destroyed or I cancel my ability.
前になにがあっても進み続ける
残念だったな　思惑が外れて
Quite a shame that things didn't work out for you.
時間がなえなあ　おい　お前の力で金を取り出せ
I don't have much time left.
Hey, you. Use your power to get the money out of there.
俺を手伝えば　全員解放してやる
If you help me, I'll release everyone.
Huh?
いや　そうだな　これからは俺と組まないか
Actually, how about this?
You can work with me from now on.
俺とお前が組めば無敵だぜ　な　どうだ
We'd be an invincible team, if I do say so myself.
Hey, what do you think?
最低の初仕事でしたの
This has been the worst first case possible.
勝手に先走って
I charged in on my own and got everyone involved...
皆さんを巻き込んで
でも　そうですわね
But...
That's right,
私絶対にお断りですの
I...
will never do that.
仲間になる
So, what do you say?
あいにくと 郵便局なんか狙うちんけなこそ泥はタイプじゃありませんの
Unfortunately, I'm not interested in petty thieves who target post offices.
それには私
And I...
Someone, please!
お願いです　誰か
もうこころに決めってますの
...I've decided it!
自分の信じた正義は決して曲げないと
I shall not go against my ideals!
そうか　残念だ
I see. Well, too bad.
That ability is powerful, but lacks speed.
あの能力　力はあってもスピードは無い
この足が言うことを聞けば
If my legs do as I tell them...
なら　ここで死ね
Have fun dying.
一度に一つしか投げなれないとは言ってないぞ
I never said that I could only throw one!
What?
へ？
Oh shit!
しまっ
<teleport>
あなたの鉄球と　私のテレポート　どっちが早いか勝負します
Why don't we see which is faster?
You know, between your ball and my teleport.
くそ
Damn.
助かったの
Are we saved?
やった
What a relief.
すげい
Amazing!
How great! We're saved!
We're safe!
やっぱり　白井さんは凄いです
Shirai-san, you're wonderful!
本当に一人で解決しちゃうなんて
You took care of this all by yourself.
Oh...
あれは一体
What was that?
私　約束します
I promise.
え？
What?
己の信念に従い　正しいと感じた行動を取るべし
Just do what you believe is right.
Umm...
I will never go against my ideals.
私も自分の信じた正義は決して曲げません
何があってもへこたれず
Whatever happens, I won't give up.
<Judgement>
きっと　白井さんのようなジャッジメントになります
I will become a member of Judgement, just like you.
その約束　私にもさせてくださいな
Hey...
...I think I'll join in on that promise.
Huh?
今まで何でも一人で出来るつもりでいましたけど
I thought I could handle anything by myself, but I guess that was pretty naive.
それはとんだ思い違い
ですから これからは二人で 一緒に一人前になってくださいます
So, why don't the two of us strive to become fully-fledged members of Judgement together?
はい
Sure.
へぇ～いい話じゃない
I see.
What a touching story.
うん　どうしたの
Huh?
What's the matter?
いいえ　別に
O-Oh, nothing...
約束ってあのことでしたのね
So that was the promise she talked about...
しかしいまさらどう謝るって
How am I supposed to apologize to her now, though?
Oh!
H-Hello, this is Shirai.
あ　はい　白井ですの
へ　初春は
Huh?
Uiharu left?
Yes. She told me she found the location of those thieves, then shot out of here.
ええ　例の車上荒らしの居場所特定したって　いきなり飛び出していたわ
あの子あれからずっと探してたのよ
She's been looking for them since then.
それで 白井さん あなたはどうするの
So, what are you going to do?
私は
I will...
己の信念に従い　正しいと感じた行動を取るべし　だっけ
Just do what you believe is right.
Was that it?
いいじゃん　それでぶつかりあって　それでも一緒に進んでいけるなら
It's fine as long as you can still work together despite your differences.
G-Get moving!
何をぐずぐずしてますの
そんなことではいつまで経っても 二人で一人前になんてなれませんわよ
You'd better get a move on, or we're never gonna become fully-fledged members of Judgement!
ああ～～世話しないな
Oh my... They're so restless.
まあ　でも　あれはあれで　青春なのかもって感じはするわね
Well, but...
...it kinda gives me a sense...
...of youth, you know?
白井さん　ちょっと早すぎませんか
Shirai-san, aren't you going too fast!?
あ　もう～　先に行きますわよ
Hurry up! I'm gonna leave you behind!
Hey! Teleporting isn't fair!
<teleport>
テレポートはなしですよ
Dear My Friend Every day & night
Always be with you
Dear My Friend every day & night
話しても　まだまだ　足りないまま
夕焼けが　街を染めてゆく
思うように　なかなか　いかない…って
気づいたら　一緒に　泣いていた
恋も　夢も　花も　虹も　風も
ぜんぶ掴もうよ
ダイジョウブ！　元気出して
私がそばにいるから
今日のミス　悔やむより　今　乗り越えて
ダイジョウブ！　迷わないで
まだ見ぬ未来へと向かって
ずっと　歩いてゆこう
Dear My Friend every day & night
Always be with you
Next Episode
黒子と初春さん青春だったんわよ
Kuroko and Uiharu-san are sure enjoying themselves.
对
这
种
事
大
家
都
积
极
万
分
Everyone
Likes
This Sort
of Thing
ジャッジメントは奥が深いですの
Judgement is a pretty complex thing.
お姉様も体験なさいます
Do you want to experience it too, Onee-sama?
次回
Next episode: Onee-sama's First Experience.
お姉さまの初体験　怖がらない
Don't be scared-
全然違うだろか
That's totally wrong!